thehomepage.com.au 2019-03-06

# 

This website is operated by Dog No. 7 Pty Ltd ACN 144 646 159 who may operate in conjunction with any one or more of W Media Holdings Pty Ltd ACN 601 487 414, W Media No. 1 Pty Ltd ACN 601 487 512, W Media No. 2 Pty Ltd ACN 602 184 412, W Media No. 3 Pty Ltd 614 926 573, W Media No. 5 Pty Ltd ACN 619 134 977, W Media No. 6 Pty Ltd ACN 619 218 325, W Media Japan Pty Ltd ACN 602 184 485, Recon Oz Pty Ltd ACN 601 487 585, Million Plus Pty Ltd ACN 122 282 599, Noonbenz Pty Ltd ACN 068 801 525 their related bodies corporate, associates and affiliates (Associates).

This Privacy Policy is intended to provide a clear and concise summary of The Home Page and W Media Holdings current approach to the handling of personal information in accordance with the Australian Privacy Principles.

We are committed to complying with the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) (Privacy Act), including the Australian Privacy Principles.

We will provide a free copy of this policy to anyone who asks for it.

By using this website, signing up to any of our accounts or services (including memberships, promotions, digital data rooms and data alerts), subscribing to any of our newsletters, providing any advertisements, contacting us through our website, or accepting our Terms and Conditions, you agree to your personal information being handled in accordance with this policy.

### What types of personal information do we collect?

Personal information means information or an opinion about an identified individual, or an individual who is reasonably identifiable, whether the information or opinion is true or not, and whether the information or opinion is recorded in a material form or not.

Examples of personal information collected by us include individuals' names, occupation, company, their source of inquiry and contact details (e.g. telephone number, email address and address), and the publications and topics of interest to individuals. For those who blog with us, personal information may also include photographs, location, profile and languages spoken.

We may collect the following personal information from job applicants, and contractors: name, employment history and experience, qualifications, date of birth, contact details, referee details, emergency contact details.

Names and contact details may also be collected from individuals representing industry related contacts.

Personal information can include sensitive information. Sensitive information is defined in the Privacy Act as information or an opinion about a person's race, ethnic origin, political opinions, membership of political associations and trade associations, religious or philosophical beliefs, sexual orientation or practices, or criminal record, health information, genetic information about an individual that is not otherwise health information, biometric information that is used for the purpose of automated biometric verification or biometric identification and biometric templates.

We do not usually collect sensitive information. We will only ever collect sensitive information in circumstances where you have consented to the collection, or we are required or authorised by law to collect the sensitive information. If sensitive information is ever collected by us, it will only ever be used for the purpose it was collected. We never use or disclose sensitive information for direct marketing purposes.

### How do we collect and hold personal information?

We generally collects personal information from:

  * individuals who deal with us in person e.g. face to face or telephone;
  * individuals who use our online subscription, listings or contact facilities, register for accounts online, or who email us about newsletters, advertising, products or services offered on or via websites that are operated by us, including but not limited to the websites hosted at but not limited to the following domains: [www.therealestateconversation.com.au](http://www.therealestateconversation.com.au/); [www.thehomepage.com.au](http://www.thehomepage.com.au/); [www.thebusinesspage.com.au](http://www.thebusinesspage.com.au/); [www.millionplus.com.au](http://www.millionplus.com.au/); [www.retalkasia.com](http://www.retalkasia.com/); [www.reconjobs.com.au](http://www.reconjobs.com.au/); [www.retirencare.com.au](http://www.retirencare.com.au/); [www.luxurylist.com.au](http://www.luxurylist.com.au/); [www.retalkmena.com](http://www.retalkmena.com/); [www.thehotelconversation.com.au](http://www.thehotelconversation.com.au/); [www.thehotelpage.com.au](http://www.thehotelpage.com.au/); [www.gapurabali.com](http://www.gapurabali.com/); [www.gapurajakarta.com](http://www.gapurajakarta.com/); 
  * Associates (as defined above);
  * our overseas affiliates and media partners;
  * co-publishers;
  * our agents, service providers and contractors;
  * property owners, property developers, real estate agents, brokers, valuers, researchers and other industry related contacts; and; 
  * referees and former employers in the case of job applicants (including through the jobs portal), suppliers and contractors. 

If you visit one of our websites, our internet service provider may record certain information about your visit, including:

  * internet address;
  * domain name;
  * internet service provider;
  * the date and time of the visit to the website;
  * any information or documentation and or data downloaded;
  * your feedback, comments and conversations;
  * the length of the session;
  * the pages accessed;
  * the website that referred to our website;
  * the type and version of the browser; and
  * the operating system used.

We are also able to collect information about email recipients including geographical location and viewing and interaction activity (such as views, bounces, clicks, replies, forwards, opt outs and links). This information is aggregated for analysis as de-identified data.

We use pixels, or transparent GIF files, on our websites to help manage online advertising and email marketing. These files enable our service providers to recognise a unique cookie in your Web browser, which in turn enables us and our service providers to learn which advertisements and emails brought you to our website, and how you use our website. GIF files are used to:

  * track responses to advertisements, emails and site content (including social media engagements);
  * determine your ability to receive HTML based emails;
  * record how many users open an email;
  * compile aggregated statistics;
  * better target interactive advertising;
  * enhance customer support and site usability; and
  * provide offers and promotions that we believe would be of interest to you.

We do not collect any of the personal information that you may input into third party search, quote and application tools available on our website/s, for example but not limited to online loan search or application tools powered by Ratesonline.com.au Pty Ltd, online enquiry tools provided by moneyQuest Australia Pty Ltd, online insurance quote forms provided by moneyQuest Insurance Services Pty Ltd, and sold data and personal data from Walk Score, and others from time to time. You should consult the relevant third parties' privacy policies for information about how they will handle your personal information.

### Consent

By accessing any of our websites, signing up to any of our accounts or services (including memberships, promotions, digital data rooms and data alerts), subscribing to any of our newsletters, providing any advertisements, contacting us through any of our websites, or accepting any terms and conditions that incorporate this Privacy Policy, you agree to your personal information being handled in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

You are not required to provide personal information to us. However, if you do not provide us with all the information we request, the services we provide to you may be affected. For example, by not providing your email address or any other personal information requested, we may not be able to communicate with you or deliver publications to you, or provide you with other updates and offers.

### Cookies and Other Technologies

Cookies and other technologies may be used by us or by third parties when you visit any of our websites or use any of our applications or related digital properties (individually and collectively, "Services"). In some cases, we may collect personal information from the cookies. 'Cookies' contain some information with a unique ID number pertaining to your computer. We may use this information to determine your usage and the Services performance.

We may also collect information about your browsing behaviour, such as but not limited to, the number of times you have visited, the date you visited and the amount of time you spent using our Services. We may also collect anonymous data (which is not personal information) about performance and errors that occur while you use our Services.

The information collected from cookies and other technologies is used solely for our internal purposes in managing our Services and improving their functionality and reliability, as well as to assist us in better targeting advertising, report statistics, analyse trends, administer our services, diagnose any errors and thereby enhancing customer support, site usability and quality.

The collection of such information, whether by us or by data aggregators, is subject to the terms set forth in this Privacy Policy.

### Disclosure of personal information

In the course of business, we may disclose personal information to:

  * users of our websites;
  * potential purchasers of businesses, advertisers, data and real estate and their professional advisers;
  * our Associates (as defined above);
  * our overseas affiliates;
  * property developers, property owners, real estate agents, brokers, valuers and other real estate industry contacts;
  * third parties where you have requested information, goods or services from them (e.g. Ratesonline.com.au Pty Ltd if you use the online loan search or application tools powered by ratesonline.com.au that are accessible from our website/s, moneyQuest Australia Pty Ltd if you use its online forms to enquire about financial advice or car loans and moneyQuest Insurance Services Pty Ltd if you use the online insurance quote forms accessible from our website/s) and others from time to time;
  * lenders and mortgage brokers;
  * insurers and insurance brokers;
  * referees and former employers (in the case of job applicants and contractors);
  * external organisations that are our agents, suppliers, service providers or contractors;
  * advertisers for marketing material;
  * syndicated listing sites;
  * our shareholders;
  * our sponsors;
  * media partners;
  * our professional advisers, such as accountants, lawyers and auditors; and
  * if required or authorised by law, regulatory bodies, government agencies and authorities, law enforcement bodies and courts.

### Why do we need personal information?

The purposes for which we collect, hold, use and disclose personal information include:

  * providing you with information about retirement and aged care;
  * sending you newsletters, publications, communications and advertising material (including third party publications, communications and advertising material);
  * providing our overseas affiliates, co-publishers and media partners with your email address so that they can send you local and or relevant versions of our publications;
  * advertising or marketing products, opportunities and services (including third party products and services);
  * responding to enquiries or providing a relevant product or service as requested;
  * providing you with information in relation to real estate or the real estate industry;
  * compiling, analysing and sharing statistics, sold data and or case studies;
  * to customise our services or advertising;
  * administration, business planning and other internal management functions and operations related to the provision or management of our products or services, including research and development;
  * debt collection;
  * complying with our legal obligations;
  * audit;
  * assessment of employment applications;
  * other purposes for which it was collected.

### Direct marketing

We may use personal information to send direct marketing material in relation to our products or services, Associates' products or services, or the products or services of third parties.

We may also disclose personal information to Associates, our overseas affiliates; our partners; co-publishers; our sponsors and other third parties, in order to facilitate direct marketing by those parties.

If you do not wish to receive marketing information from us, you may at any time opt-out of receipt of further marketing communications by contacting our Privacy Officer (contact details below). If direct marketing is by email, you may also use the unsubscribe function.

You should also contact our Privacy Officer if you do not wish us to disclose your personal information to third parties for direct marketing purposes.

### Government related identifiers

We do not use any government related identifiers, such as driver's licence numbers, as its own internal identifier of any individual. We will not use or disclose any government related identifiers other than in accordance with the Privacy Act, or as otherwise required or authorised by law.

### Data integrity and security

We endeavour to ensure that all personal information we hold is accurate, complete and up-to-date. To assist us with this, individuals should contact us if any of their personal information changes, or if they believe that the personal information we have is not accurate or complete.

We take reasonable steps to protect the personal information that they hold from misuse, interference or loss, or from unauthorised access, modification or disclosure.

If we no longer require personal information that we hold (including when we are no longer required by law to keep records relating to you), we will take such steps as are reasonable in the circumstances to destroy the information or ensure that the information is de-identified.

### Disclosure overseas

We may disclose your personal information to overseas recipients globally this may include but is not limited to locations such as, New Zealand, Japan, Indonesia, Singapore, Malaysia, China, Mongolia, Thailand, other Asian countries, United Arab Emirates, M.E.N.A and the United States of America.

By accessing any of our websites or services you consent to disclosure of your personal information anywhere in the world on the basis that we will not be accountable under the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) or equivalent overseas laws, and you will not be able to seek redress under the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) and may not be able to seek redress under overseas law if the overseas recipient handles your information in a way that breaches the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth). Overseas recipients may not be subject to any privacy obligations that are similar to the Australian Privacy Principles, and may be subject to a foreign law that could compel the disclosure of personal information to a third party such as an overseas authority.

### Access and correction

Individuals can ask us for access to their personal information held by us by sending a written request to our Privacy Officer at the address below.

We do not impose a charge for making a request for access, however we may charge for reasonable administrative costs incurred in providing access.

You can ask us to correct or update your personal information. We do not impose any charge with respect to requests for correction or updates.

Before correcting or providing access to personal information in response to a request, we will require your identity to be confirmed.

Requests for access or correction may be refused upon the grounds contained in the Privacy Act. If we refuse to provide access, or to correct personal information, we will provide you with reasons for the refusal.

### Complaints

Privacy related complaints should be directed to Williams Media's Privacy Officer in writing at the email or postal address shown below. No charge will be imposed for the making of a complaint, or for dealing with the complaint.

Once a complaint has been lodged, our Privacy Officer will acknowledge its receipt to you as soon as possible.

We will endeavour to respond to your complaint as soon as possible.

We will do our best to ensure that our investigation is completed, and a decision on your complaint is communicated to you, within 30 days of our receipt of the written complaint. We will inform you if we need more time. If we are not able to resolve your complaint to your satisfaction you may also contact the Australian Information Commissioner.

### Office of the Australian Information Commissioner

GPO Box 5218

SYDNEY NSW 2001

Telephone: 1300 363 992

Website: [www.oaic.gov.au](http://www.oaic.gov.au/)

### Employee records

Employee records are exempt from the operation of the Australian Privacy Principles.

### Privacy Officer contact details

Williams Media's Privacy Officer’s contact details are:

Address: Privacy Officer

Level 34, Waterfront Place, 1 Eagle St,

Brisbane City QLD 4000

Telephone: +61 (03) 9486 0288 or 1300 377 037 (within Australia)

Email: [privacy@williamsmedia.com.au](mailto:privacy@williamsmedia.com)

### Changes to this policy

This Privacy Policy may be varied from time to time without notice.

This Privacy Policy was last updated on 15 April 2016.

### Unsubscribe

Where we have collected your personal information from one of our overseas affiliates, partners, co-publishers, contributors and bloggers that affiliate has advised us and understands that you have provided your consent to the use of your personal information for the purpose of receiving email publications, text messages and other electronic communications including The Home Page, and for direct marketing purposes.

If you do not wish to receive The Home Page, or any other Williams Media publications or marketing material, from us, you may at any time opt-out by contacting our Privacy Officer (contact details above). If the communication is by email, you may also use the unsubscribe function.

You should also contact our Privacy Officer if you do not want us to disclose your personal information to third parties for direct marketing purposes.

### Legal and disclaimer

This publication is protected by copyright. All rights are reserved. No part of this work may be reproduced or copied in any form without the written permission of the publisher.

Because the information contained on this website and associated pages is general and has been prepared without consideration of any specific viewers legal, financial, tax, insurance, real estate objectives, investment objectives, risk profile, immigration citizenship, carer, health, medical needs or advice, financial situation or needs, we strongly recommend that an independent adviser/s should be consulted before any investment, financial, real estate, health, insurance, immigration or other decision is made.

While the information contained on this website is based on information from sources, which are considered reliable, Williams Media, its officers, employees, bloggers, partners, affiliates and co-publishers and consultants do not represent, warrant or guarantee, expressly or impliedly, that the information contained in this article or blog is complete or accurate.

We do not accept any responsibility to inform you of any matter that subsequently comes to its notice, which may affect any of the information contained in this document.

To the extent permitted by law we exclude any liability, including any liability for negligence, for any loss, including indirect or consequential damages arising from or in relation to the use of any of the information on this website or associated pages.
